

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

Senior Software Developer | Phoenix, Arizona

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin-Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Systems

EXPERIENCE

CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

Sr. Application Developer: September 2021 - Present

• Senior Application Developer with CBRE Location Intelligence.

Theorem | Los Angeles, California

Engineering Manager: March 2021 - August 2021

- Lead a team of remote software engineers, overseeing the architecture, development, and delivery of custom software for clients.
- Managed nine direct reports, coaching and supporting each engineer's career growth, and evaluating their performance.
- Prioritized, delegated, and supervised all engineers' tasks and deliverables.
- Communicated and collaborated with product managers, designers, stakeholders, and clients to drive the project execution.

Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

Staff Engineer: May 2019 - March 2021

Senior Developer: December 2018 - May 2019

- Lead a team of developers and testers by prioritizing tasks, delegating duties, and guiding projects to successful and on-time delivery.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture for greenfield development, allowing developers to rapidly begin coding and reducing the time needed to deliver a minimum viable product.
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage in all applications, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and led successful effort to refactor applications to follow these guidelines.

Carvana | Tempe, Arizona

Software Engineer: January 2018 - December 2018

- Primary job function was back-end development to create and maintain the APIs and microservices which powered carvana.com using C#, .NET & .NET Core.
- Supported front end development to maintain and enhance a mobile responsive UI for vehicle inventory search engine (JavaScript ES6, React & Redux).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver the best UX.

CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

Application Developer: January 2011 – January 2018 GIS Technician: March 2008 – January 2011

• Developed web and desktop applications which provided mapping, site selection, and data analysis tools for real estate brokers and their clients using C#, .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, and Python.

ABOUT ME

My name is Matthew Callahan, and I am a player-coach in the software world. I enjoy writing code as well as leading my team and mentoring developers. I have over ten years of experience in agile software development and continuing to learn the ever-changing landscape of programming is my passion.

CONTACT

Email: matthew.callahan@outlook.com

Phone: 630-988-1555

Homepage: mfcallahan.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GitHub: github.com/mfcallahan

Blog: mfcallahan.blog

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python

Frameworks

.NET, Node.js, Angular, Vue.js, React, ArcGIS

Testing

NUnit, Jasmine, Mocha, Selenium

Dev Tools

Azure, Git, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, Splunk, SQL Server

resume ver 2021.10.1